Keep your heart open.
Hamnet is a drama, romance film directed by Chloé Zhao.
The powerful story of love and loss that inspired the creation
of Shakespeare's timeless masterpiece, Hamlet.
Agnes, played by Jessie Buckley.
Will, played by Paul Mescal.
Mary, played by Emily Watson.
Bartholomew, played by Joe Alwyn.
Hamnet, played by Jacobi Jupe.
Hamlet, played by Noah Jupe.
Hamnet  is a 2025 biographical historical tragedy film directed by Chloé Zhao, who co-wrote
the screenplay with Maggie O'Farrell, based on the 2020 novel by O'Farrell.
The film dramatises the family life of William Shakespeare and his wife Anne
Hathaway as they cope with the death of their 11-year-old son Hamnet.
It stars Jessie Buckley and Paul Mescal as Agnes and William, alongside
Emily Watson, Joe Alwyn, and Noah Jupe in supporting roles.
Hamnet had its world premiere at the 52nd Telluride Film Festival on 29 August 2025 and received a
limited theatrical release by Focus Features in the United States and Canada on 26 November.
It received a wide theatrical release on 5 December and was released by
Universal Pictures in the United Kingdom on 9 January 2026.
The film received critical acclaim, with the performances of
Buckley and Mescal receiving particular praise.
It was listed among the top ten films of 2025 by the American Film Institute.
The film won Best Motion Picture – Drama and Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama (for Buckley) at the 83rd
Golden Globe Awards, and Buckley additionally won the Critics’ Choice Award for Best Actress.
The film received eight nominations at the 98th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, Best Director for Zhao and Best Actress for Buckley.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, grief,
death of son, woman director, 16th century.
The tone is emotional.